Let's discuss about the system.
We start to process.
So in this section, we will go through some of the classes which are responsible for the system UI
start up.
So here is a high level overview of how the system UI is started.
OK, so as you can see here, the single process starts the systems of the systems tower internet star
system UI and the System UI finally initialize this whole system UI components.
So this is how the system usually starts.
If you haven't heard about Tiger, it's one of the process which starts during the Android bulldozers,
so it's one of the first Android process to get started and all the rest of the processes it started
from the side.
And the system server is one of the most important process which side got started and the systems are
always responsible for a lot of other things.
Systems are also stouts all the services within Android, and it is also responsible for starting the
system UI.
So on a very high level.
So this is the process.
So the cycle is started by kernel.
The cycle starts system server and system server is responsible for starting all the services, including
system UI app.
And finally, the system UI actually initialize us all the system UI components like navigation, bar
status, bar closed and all other advanced.
Now, let's dig a little bit deeper into that, so here is a sequence, a diagram of how the system
you get started.
So as you can see here, we have airman's, which is nothing but activity management service.
And then we have the system server, which is responsible for starting lot of services, including system,
UI app.
And then we have the system UI application here, which is basically a class and the system UI service.
This is again a class.
We will have a look at this class and then the system UI itself.
So the first step is that the system server receives signal from the spigot.
So this diagram shows the process starting from systems.
OK, so once the system Sava got the signal from Saigal because this particular function started, the
service assigned the start of the services enter core start system UI function, and this started singing
a function will create an instance of the system UI application and the all clear of this class is triggered.
The system UI application extends to application.
The method will have a look at these classes in the next section, but for now, keep in mind that system
UI application extends that application class, and it has an own create function, which gets triggered
when it is instantiate.
And after this on Create the Activity Management Service receives this trigger.
It calls the start service function, and it calls Subsystem UI service and the system UI calls the
on grid.
It has an own create function which gets executed, and this will start service if needed from the system
UI application and then run system UI application bolster start method, which finally triggers the
system UI.
So this is the overall sequence diagram of how that works.
So now let's do a cold walk through soil and visit all these classes and see how that works.